it is my great pleasure to introduce
Joel Robinson from Moody's who is going
to talk about not AI
[Applause]
search hello okay the mic works amazing
hi everyone I'm Joel Robinson thank you
so much for coming to my talk revisiting
the basics how round robin improv search
relevance for today's talk we're going
to follow this agenda here first I'll
give a brief introduction about myself
then we'll talk about the problem
statement what are the issues we're
having searching on moodys.com
afterwards we're going to explore some
Solutions in order to address these
issues afterwards we'll talk about the
algorithm
implementation then we'll get into the
results s how did everything change on
our search experience and then lastly
we'll wrap up with a with a conclusion
and a short
Q&A all right so here's a little bit
about
me once again I'm Joel Robinson I'm a
senior software engineer at Moody's I've
been with Moody for a little under six
years now and three of those years I
spent on the search Squad now during my
time at Moody's I've seen search change
exponentially
I saw us use solar and fusion then
deprecating fusion and building our own
in-house search API and then most
recently moving our main search
experience off of solar and onto AWS
open search and what we're going to talk
about today is an initiative we took
after taking that transition to open
search so let's talk about what it's
actually like to search on moodys.com
today here is our search results page
it's a pretty standard search results
page the users land here after typing
query in our search bar and hitting
enter what I'd like to note is that this
page is comprised of multiple tabs you
have an all Tab and then several other
vertical
tabs the all tab is a culmination of the
results after hitting seven different
indexes in open search and then each of
the individual tabs correspond to a
single index in open
search each tab has its own open search
search template so it has its own
algorithm curated for the res the re the
relevance excuse me for each
tab so now let's talk about the
individual verticals that we serve and
what the data is
like first we have
organizations now our organizations
represent different companies and their
subsidiaries they're important because
users would need to navigate to our
company's Pages quickly and obtain all
the information pertaining to a specific
org next we have reports and the reports
represent the research documents that we
publish
in-house the content can can be anything
from sector analysis to company
comparisons to different rating actions
for an
entity next we have deals and programs
so deals are structured Finance deals
and what's important to note about this
data type is that we need to make sure
that our deals are sorted based off of
the closing
date next we have topics and topics are
pages on our site that address topical
information like esgs or the banking
sector
next we have events so users can
actually search a topic and see a list
of events that correspond to that topic
and then register for them these can be
in person or
online we also serve analyst data so
these are analysts within Moody folks
who specialize on a different sector who
publish their own
research and then lastly we have our
newest data set Solutions and services
and this tab corresponds to some of the
products and services that we provide at
Moody's so users can search for
them now i' like to note that these two
verticals organizations and reports are
the most important for
us our users love orgs and reports and
I'll get into the reasons why in a
little bit later and you'll see more of
the Monopoly man to
come so now we know what it's like
generally what is like to search on
mood.com what our search results page is
but let's get into some of the pain
points some of the issues that we're
experiencing first we want to be people
Centric so let's talk about the actors
within our
system we have Dora Dora is our user
Dora is an archetype that we use
in-house to explain a user who likes to
take their time on the site likes to
navigate page to Page search for
different
organizations read different
reports next we have our
stakeholders now these are folks like
product owners subject matter
experts folks who have a vision of what
it's supposed to be like to search on
moodys.com they also know folks like
Dora really
well and then lastly we have the
engineers people like me people who have
to build the thing maintain the thing
folks to work on data ingestion and
search
relevance now in any good system we need
to make sure there's balance here we
need to make sure that we're balancing
the wants and needs of every single
person that we discuss our users our
stakeholders and the
engineers so I want I want you to pay
attention to the top half of my screen
for the comprehensive view or the all
tab to reiterate the all tab is has one
search algorithm that handles data for
seven different search
indexes It's a combination of all the
search results for a given
Care on the bottom half of the page we
have an example of our vertical views so
in this case it's
organization each of these vertical
views only correspond to a single index
and the SE open search search templates
are curated for that specific use case
now here are some of the pain points by
having two different views to show
similar data number
one sometimes we see that there is a
difference between the content that is
served on the all Tab versus the
vertical tabs and we'll I'll show you an
example of this in the next
slide number two we have seven different
we have several different search
algorithms to generate this one single
page so in this case we're actually
talking about
eight different algorithms for one
page and then lastly we talked about the
all page the all
tab since it's a combination of
different
indexes handling the battling
boost between the different fields that
we have to manage is often difficult our
search template for the all tab has
become one monolith of a template we
have to handle different fields make
sure that we're showing recent reports
but then also the most popular orgs but
then making sure we don't forget about
the analysts and God forbid if the last
name of the analyst is
Ford right so this causes a lot of
different search problems for us and it
makes it hard to make incremental
improvements in our search
relevance so let's get back to that
first point there being a difference
between the content surge on our all
pill versus our individ
verticals so I blew up the screenshots
for you on the left you have the all
pill and on the right you have the
organization's
pill in this case I was the user and I
was searching for the query
GM I am looking for General Motors
Company but if you
look I'm getting GM group limited as my
first result on the all
tab but on the vertical tab I'm getting
what I'm expecting General Motors
Company these differing search results
can cause a confusing and frustrating
experience for our
users Dora may like to explore but we
don't want her to get lost on her
journey and stakeholders have brought
this issue to us multiple times we can't
understand why their users are
experienced such a dissonance
now let's talk about our search metrics
here are some of the metrics that we we
track I'll let you guys take this in for
a little
bit I know they're not
great and we'll try to tackle this a
little bit later
on so now that we talked about some of
the pain points about searching on
moodys.com for our search results page
let us turn them into actionable
steps let's make acceptance
criteria number one we want to increase
our
maintainability we talked about us
having eight different open search
search templates to render a single
page why don't we reduce the amount of
those
templates why not use the individual
verticals that we have those search
templates and then create emerging
strategy to create our all
tab that way we don't have to deal with
the battling
Boost number two we want to provide
consistent search
results remember our GM query we're
getting two different ORS as a top
result on the same page that's a really
confusing experience for our users so
let's avoid that going
forward and number three we want to make
sure we don't decrease any of our search
relevancy score metrics especially for
ER or
dcg they were already low let's make
sure we don't
regress so now that we understand the
issue let's look at our possible
solutions our first possibility our
first candidate is a standard round
robin G an org
get a report get a topic or report topic
until we create our results list for our
all
tab our second option is round robin and
blocks ofen two orgs two reports two
topics two ORS two reports two topics
until we create our all
Tab and then our third option is
converting our open search scores into
posterior values and then merging on
those scores essentially let's hit open
search get the scores back normalize
these scores and then merge the results
together to create our all
pill now let's talk about the framework
of our
experiment remember our user
Dora Dora loves orgs and reports in fact
some of our users have a specific
portfolio of companies that they need to
keep tabs on so they want to see the
latest research about these companies
and they want to make sure that they're
they're in the know of anything that's
changed around
them and our stakeholders they love
research and they love orgs because they
know Dora does right this is what drives
our business this is our bread and
butter so since most of our folks that
use our site care about orgs and Report
the most we're actually going to use
this for our experiment it makes up most
of our course purp
anyways continuing on the framework
front we're going to run an experiment
and calculate rbo rank bias overlap and
expected reciprocal rank we're going to
use rank bias overlock to determine how
similar our three candidates are to what
we currently have in production we want
to make sure that we're not creating too
jarring of a new experience we don't
want to scare Dora
away most of our uses on our site are
very loyal they've been with Moody for a
long time so let's make sure Dora stays
with us Dora knows the system so let's
not confuse
her and then we're going to use err to
look at the relevancy at our top results
we want to make sure that we're
providing the best results at the top of
our
list
historically we saw on a 3-month time
frame only 13 people hit page two 13 in
3 months so we need to make sure that
our top results are the
best so now let's look at the experiment
results here's rank buers overlap at 100
for our three candidates so comparing
our three candidates to what's currently
in
production I want you to pay attention
to the mean here
you can see that round robin and Round
Robin and blocks of
n have a much higher rbo score than the
posterior values meaning that these two
ranked
lists are very similar to what we
currently have in prod indicating that
we won't have that jarring experience
that might scare Dora
away now let's look at it at the top 10
so rbo at
10 and if you look at the mean
again round robin is the
winner giving us a good indication that
we would still have a good experience
and Dora won't be confused if we
implement it to
prod so let's actually look at the r the
ER R score at
10 so if we compare round robin to
global global in this case is what's
currently in prod our
control and again looking at the
mean we can see an increase
here we're moving our err score from
0.57 to
0.63 we're actually seeing an
improvement in our relevance
all right so you saw the
experiment and the
results I'm sure that you can imagine
round robin was our
winner so we're going to use round robin
as our merging strategy to create our
all pill and this is how we're going to
do
it we're going to use open search's m
search endpoint they're multi-arch
feature in order to send our requests
and then receive the result back so
essentially we're going to use the
vertical search templates send one
request in parallel and then receive
those results back to concatenate our
all
pill then remember these
two yeah they love ORS and reports we
know we get it so since Dora and our
stakeholders both love or organizations
and reports we're going to actually
prioritize this data for them making
sure that they get exactly what they
need at the top of their
list so we come up with the FI the final
strategy
here we're going to alternate between
organizations and reports for our top
10 then we're going to complete the
result list by performing round robin
across the rest of our data
so to
reiterate we go back and forth between
ORS and reports to create our top
10 and then round robin to fill the rest
of the
list it's a very simple
algorithm but it's also very efficient
runs in linear time and then having that
coupled with the m search feature of
open search
we're able to see great
improvements very efficiently and the
results here's our new SE here's our new
search results
page so let's talk about some of the
wins by implementing round robin as our
merging
strategy again always wanting to be
people focused so here's
Dora Dora gets to see all of her
favorite content first organizations and
reports
always our stakeholders get the
consistent results that they've been
asking for so no more confusing Journeys
on the
site and then lastly the engineers folks
like me we have one less thing to
maintain one less thing to worry
about so the consistency problem we were
having on the all pill versus the
individual vertical
pills let's see how we did here same
query
GM I'm looking for General Motors
Company and now we're getting GM as a
top result on our all
pill and we're also getting General
Motors on the organization pill
consistency and if you look closely you
can see round robin at play
here so on the all pill we have
organizations then are report
then another org then a report and that
second org matches the second org on the
organization's
tab so let's look at the
metrics so we Ed our implicit
judgments in order to see how our
relevance is doing on the site our
implic judgment query set is a set that
contains 5,000 queries and they were
chosen from our query logs during a
six-month time frame they were chosen
using a probability proportional
sampling and we use a hierarchical basic
in model to generate the
judgments and these are the metrics that
we
track average expected reciprocal rank
some discounted accumulative gain mean
average Precision average precision and
average age and
days I'd like to note that average age
in days is a stat that we only look at
for report
Dora doesn't want a report from 15 years
ago 10 years ago she wants to see what's
recent and here are metrics
now the controls what's currently in
prod round
robin and if you take a
look we're seeing an increase across the
board
what I'd like to note is that an average
uh increase in average Asian days is not
a good
thing we want to make sure we're showing
Dora fresh reports but what I will say
is by nature of the round robin
algorithm the problem is now localized
to just the reports search template we
know exactly where the recency script is
we know exactly how to tune it so now
addressing the issue of recency for
reports is very simple and
straightforward and then we'll be able
to reap the benefits on our all pill
immediately but if these scores don't
impress you we also tested for
significance we ran a dependent
two-sided tea test against our control
and Round Robin to see if we're seeing
any significant
changes and again they
are across the board we're seeing
significant
changes the only one where we don't see
a significant change is some
dcg but it's on a different scale you
can't really compare query to query so
we really can't test for significance
there the important one to note is that
ER we're seeing an a significant change
here and then again average agent days
we know this is an issue we know this is
a problem but we also know how to tackle
it so it's not a problem going
forward let's talk about
maintainability our product owner
actually came to me with a request they
wanted to add a new index to our search
experience and I said okay sure no
problem I knew with having round robin
this is an easy
ask remember Solutions and services our
newest data set
now with round robin I just had to plug
it in the
loop and it appeared on our allad on our
all
tab this is such an easy
win using round robin we saw an
extensibility increase we're able to add
new content very easily and then rank
with
intent if one day we don't care about
orgs and reports for whatever reason we
can switch it to analysts making sure
that they get prioritized or Solutions
and services now we have the ability and
flexibility to actually make changes to
our
ranking now it's not always sunshines
and
rainbows door isn't always happy there's
sometimes challenges along the way and
bumps in the road so let's talk about
them first
challenge custom pagination
custom pagination proved to be very
tedious and tricky to handle it was so
tedious and tricky that our front-end
lead told us not to do it he straight up
said don't do it use open searches out
of the box pagination feature it's not
worth a headache save yourself the
time but we knew from our experiment how
much we can actually gain by using round
robin as our merging strategy so after
conversations and ping P pushing back
excuse
me we implemented it but he did not
lie the next challenge we faced is
actually moving our API from a stateless
design to a stateful design we actually
had to pass the state of the users from
the back end to the front end and back
and forth
again all because of custom
pagination so picture this you need to
handle whether or not a user is
paginating sequentially or skipping
through your list you have to know
whether or not a user is paginating
forward or paginating backwards going
from the first page to the very last
page you have to handle all cases and in
order to do so we needed to know where
our users were and where they were going
and how much information they needed so
the only way we could do this is passing
this information back and forth
and the last challenge again on the
pagination theme round drin simple to
impl implement pagination not so much
the code for pagination became bloed
fairly
quickly after multiple rounds of
refactoring and iterating on our code we
were able to slim it
down but I think we can even go a little
bit further with
this but this was a challenge we knew
that pagination was going to be
difficult this is a challenge that we're
willing to tackle because we know the
benefits that we're going to have plus
like I said
before only 13 people really hit page
two in three months so even though it's
an important issue that we had to
address we knew that it was a smaller
one that only affected a small scope of
people
so now let's wrap everything
up here's the acceptance criteria we
talked about in the beginning we wanted
to increase
maintainability we wanted to provide
consistent search results and then we
wanted to make sure we didn't decrease
our relevancy score metrics for err or
dcg we were able to increase our
maintainability we got rid of of the all
tabs search
template a template that was the longest
one in our repo and the most
complex and now by Nature round robin
any incremental changes we make on our
individual verticals we will be able to
reap those benefits directly on the all
pill
automatically we're able to provide
consistent search results so no more
confusing GM queries where we're getting
two different orgs as our top result on
the same page
because of implementing round robin our
research results will always be
consistent and we did it decrease our
relevancy score metrics for ER or
dcg in fact we saw an increase a
significant increase in a lot of our
score our relevancy score
metrics so with that being
said thank you so much for listening to
my
talk do you have any questions
[Applause]
why look there's a
question thank you for not making me
walk um yeah you you had
um sorry I forgot my question you had
uh you you had like six different other
verticals that you had
you're using M search um did that
immediately like implementing the M
search did that immediately increase the
load on on your search aside from doing
a single template to doing six
simultaneous templates to to pull all
that back we didn't see any any
difference in performance in that way
actually so I think actually it's it's
fine using M search we also didn't see
any any latency it was pretty fast since
the requests are sent in parallel we get
the results back all at once as well so
it was pretty
good so I have a a question with these
multiple categories yeah um had you ever
considered going a step further and
rather than having aggregated results do
like a Federated experience where like
you would be having one section that was
just reports one section that was you
know just organizations or is this
typically you know your users don't
really understand the categorization and
just one of results it h that's a great
question that is a great question I
think right now remember Dora being like
super loyal and like knowing how the
system
works this new search results experience
mimics what we had in the past because
we didn't want to drastically change
what we currently have so I think in the
future we can definitely look on
innovating and and splitting up the
experience in the verticals and showing
it in a different way however I think we
want to stick towards a more traditional
layout just because that is what's our
customers are used to but we do have
plans for switching up the search
experiment I mean experience um pretty
drastically but that's further down the
line as we slowly slowly teach our users
how to like use search in a different
way and in the way that we want them to
think like
forwardly I'm going to cut
across thank you Jo well done thank you
um your third attempt which was not a
winner and the metrics were bad um did
did you attempt to rank the different
categories using like the best score of
each individual search because you
talked about a uh open search score
posterior um okay so I guess my question
is the following uh you mentioned that
you're normalizing the scores yeah and
as a search practitioner I was always
told by Doug my neighbor over the years
here that bm25 scores cannot be
normalized can you elaborate on the
normalization process I'm just curious
even though that was not your winner but
there's an interesting technique there
yeah I actually wasn't the person who
implemented this specific experiment I I
can speak to that actually David can our
part it is most assuredly the case that
you can normalize bm25 scores or any
model scores across a fixed set of
results
by dividing by the sum of the results to
put them on the scale of 0 to one this
gives you a reasonable approximation of
the posterior probability of that item
for a given query and as such you could
merge them it was a straw man
strategy Doug was
wrong I did not say that Doug was wrong
pardon
me I've given up on going all the way
down um thank you uh I was just
wondering so for the round robin two
where you um presented two results from
uh this template two results from
another um did
you have a sense of why that did not
perform as well and then kind
more generally what is
the
like did you think it all about or or
like kind of try to characterize what
the relevance context is for this
General search
because uh intuitively it seems like if
you're just going you know from category
to category and presenting uh the top
result it
could be a little bit um jarring like as
you see like you know company report
company
report um so so I'm curious about how
you think of that problem of like what
it would mean for a user to search for
like GM in just a very general
context okay uh I don't know if those
questions make sense but yeah let me let
me make sure I'm gonna feed it back to
you and just confirm whether or not I'm
understanding correctly so the it kind
of sounds like two different questions
like the first one you're asking about
um round robin with blocks of K right
and if I have any sense of why it
performed a little bit worse than our
traditional round robin that's correct
yeah okay um on on that and just just to
um sorry to just clarify one more I mean
I think that the relationship between
the two questions is that um
uh like you
would if you if you think of some if you
have a model of relevance for what these
General results are are are supposed to
look like you know that might be the
thread that helps you think about like
why you know showing the top two from
each category could be worse than
showing just this one and then that one
and and so
onh yeah I see where you're getting at
if I had to take a hunch just based off
of like the numbers and knowing our data
and users reports are often prioritized
people like to read reports and they're
often clicked on quite a lot um
especially in the context of our search
results page so with that being said
having reports be number two I think is
reason why we're seeing a little bit of
a boost here and um a closer similarity
to what we currently have in production
today um does that kind of answer your
question
RJ Lee asks when calculating the
dcg and somebody else just popped in how
is the relevance of the results
determined is a human marking results is
relevant or not
relevant okay yeah so for dcg and all of
our relevancy score metrics we are
using excuse me as I go through all of
these we're using this framework which
is actually something that was presented
at hyack um 2022 by Renee
and and it's using probability
proportional sampling sampling and a
hierarchical based model to generate the
judgments so it's based off of real
click counts and it's supposed to be
representative of what our user traffic
is and the information needs of the
users so that's how we actually generate
the um the scores for
are different methods
here and Mustafa asks thanks for an
interesting talk do you do anything
special queries that perhaps fit more to
a specific vertical EG if a user is
looking for events SL deals and
indicates it in their
[Music]
query currently currently no but we do
have that information those information
needs within our explicit and implicit
judgment so we can understand where the
what the user actually wants um however
we don't do anything special when we get
the the actual query sent to our system
and producing the results
themselves hi thanks very much for the
talk it was very um enlightening I I was
interested in your example query of GM
yes and you know the obvious
organization is General Motors yes um so
that that comes first in your search
results and then a report on General
Motors I'm assuming is a second and then
you've got another another organization
there that's probably significantly less
relevant than the first
organization um and so I'm assuming that
the next report that comes under that is
again a report on General Motors and it
made me think about um some work i' done
previously with uh sponsored ads coming
up and and we measured click-through
rate at position and the first three
results were sponsored search results
and the the rest were organic and when
we looked at our click-through rate by
position we saw slightly lower ctrs on
the first three results and then kind of
um increase ctrs on the lower results I
was just Ed have you looked at CTR by
position and do you see a similar
pattern of cuz it would seem that you're
going to have a lot more reports than
you are organizations that match and uh
you know just curious yeah so right now
we do I can I guess that's kind of what
we why we use um the Precision magic to
kind of see where and how many relevant
documents we're actually getting for a
given query the hard and interesting
part about it is that GM could someone
could be looking for these deals over
here this um GM Corp pass through um so
we need to actually
manage different kinds of intents
because we don't actually know which
users coming and what they're actually
looking for so I think that
like it's very much
so important to see see where the
clicker weight is but then we also have
to couple that with the actual user
intent and I think as we grow our our
data sets and our implicit judgments and
our our evaluation system we'll be able
to get detailed and fine-tune that kind
of information but right now we don't
have
that all right are there any other
questions let's thank our speaker again
thank you
[Applause]